Guide to William and Sally Rhoads Collection of Elverhoj, 1887-1985 (bulk 1901-1942)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
William and Sally Rhoads Collection of Elverhoj
1887-1985
1901-1942
Rhoads, William Bertolet, 1944-
2.3 cubic feet (6 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
This collection consists of artwork, correspondence, printed ephemera, photographs, and publications created by or related to the Elverhoj Colony of Artists and Craftsmen (1912-1934) and its founding members, particularly A. H. (Anders Hansen) Andersen.
Historical Note
The Elverhoj Colony of Artists and Craftsmen was founded in 1912 in Milton-on-Hudson, New York, by Danish-American artists A. H. (Anders Hansen) Andersen (1874-1944) and Johannes Morton. The name "Elverhøj" translates from Danish as "Elves' Hill." Founding members of the colony also included painter James Scott, his sisters--textile artists Bessie Scott and Henrietta Scott Miller--printmaker Ralph M. Pearson, and silversmith Joseph Popelka, all of whom relocated to the Hudson Valley from Racine, Wisconsin. The colony was best known for its jewelry and metal-work, but they offered instruction in painting, printmaking, bookbinding, and weaving as well. In addition to its role as a studio for resident artists and a workshop for art instruction, the colony also hosted theater performances, exhibitions, concerts, and lectures.
The Colony operated The Elverhoj Art Shop in Poughkeepsie, NY, where they sold crafts for many years. In addition to this Poughkeepsie presence, the Elverhoj Colony was also patronized by Vassar president Henry Noble MacCracken, as well as Vassar faculty members Oliver Samuel Tonks and Lucy Maynard Salmon, and Vassar students. A number of Vassar College class rings in the 1910s were also designed by Elverhoj artists. The Elverhoj Colony closed in 1934, when A. H. Andersen lost the property to foreclosure.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of artwork, correspondence, printed ephemera, photographs, and publications created by or related to the Elverhoj Colony of Artists and Craftsmen (1912-1934) and its founding members, particularly A. H. (Anders Hansen) Andersen.
Arrangement
The collection is organized in six series: Series I. Artwork, 1901-1940; Series II. Photographs, 1905-1934; Series III. Letters and Financial Records, 1914-1942, 1985; Series IV. Printed Images and Ephemera, 1887-1937; Series V. Publications, 1912-1941; Series VI. Silverware, undated.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Elverhoj: the arts and crafts colony at Milton-on-Hudson by William B. Rhoads and Leslie Melvin.
Elverhoj Colony of Artists and Craftsmen. Vassar College Subject Files, Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries.
Vassar College Class Rings, 1920, 1922. Vassar College Realia Collection, Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries.
Separated Materials
Three publications were removed from the collection and catalogued separately: "John Bauer: Bland Tomtar och Troll" (1918); Kirstein, Gustav, "Max Klinger: Sechs farbige Wiedergaben seiner Werke"; and Winther, Christian, "Hjortens Flugt (Jubeludgave)," 1898.
Subject Headings
Names:
Anderson, Anders, 1874-1944; Pearson, Ralph M., 1883-1958
Organizations:
Elverhoj (Art colony)
Subjects:
Art, Danish; Artist colonies--New York (State)--20th century; Arts and crafts movement--United States; Danish Americans--New York (State); Decorative arts--New York (State)--20th century
Places:
Milton-on-Hudson (N.Y.)
Document Types:
Bookplates; Correspondence; Drawings (visual works); Etchings (prints); Financial records; Paintings (visual works); Pamphlets; Photographs; Printed ephemera; Prints (visual works); Publications; Realia; Watercolors (paintings)
VCL Categories:
Art and Artists; Local History
Encoding Information
Encoded by Emma Gronbeck, June 2024.
Acquisition Information
Gift of William and Sally Rhoads, October 2022. (M2022-009)
The Ralph Pearson print featuring a poem by Zona Gale was the gift of Adelaide Underhill, 1936.
Series List
- Series I. Artwork, 1901-1940; (Boxes 1, 4-6)
  This series contains original works of art in pencil, ink, and watercolor--as well as handmade prints--created by members of the Elverhoj Colony of Artists and Craftsmen, including A. H. Andersen, Ralph M. Pearson, and James Scott. The creator of many works in this series is unknown, particularly among the craft designs and renderings of products created by the Elverhoj Colony.
  Organized into seven subseries by subject or form and sub-arranged alphabetically by author or title.
- Series II. Photographs, 1905-1934; (Boxes 1, 4)
  This series contains photographs of Elverhoj-made crafts, such as lighting fixtures, jewelry, and silverware; Elverhoj classes or events; and other Scandinavian craftsmen and their work.
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
- Series III. Letters and Financial Records, 1914-1942, 1985; (Boxes 1-2)
  This series contains a small collection of letters, primarily with A. H. Andersen as the recipient, as well as receipts and invoices for purchases of materials and services for the Elverhoj Colony made by A. H. Andersen.
- Series IV. Printed Images and Ephemera, 1905-1934; (Boxes 1, 4)
  This series contains announcements, invitations, pamphlets, and programs related to Elverhoj events, exhibitions, and theatrical performances, as well as several items related to local or related organizations such as The Half-Moon antique shop and the Zodiac Artist Colony. Also included are printed copies of bookplates and cards created by Elverhoj artists, including printed duplicates of original cards and bookplates found in Series I. Artwork. Additional materials include printed images from the late 19th and early 20th-centuries, some of which feature artwork from Elverhoj artists and others which display artwork from Scandinavian and German artists who may have been an influence on the Elverhoj style.
  Organized into eight subseries by form, sub-arranged alphabetically by artist or title.
- Series V. Publications, 1912-1941; (Boxes 2-4)
  This series consists of copies of publications including The Craftsman and The Touchstone, which contain articles or references to Elverhoj, as well as examples of Elverhoj artists' work.
- Series VI. Silverware, undated; (Box 5)
  This series contains six silver teaspoons, all marked "ELVERHOJ."
Container List
- Series I. Artwork, 1901-1940
  - Bookplate and Card Designs
    - Nelson, Geraldine D., undated; [Print. 6 3/8 in x 5 in] (Folder 1.1)
    - Opffer, Ivan, "Christmas 1913" to Elverhoj, 1913 Dec 24; [Pen and ink. 5 5/8 in x 3 1/2 in] (Folder 1.1)
    - Pearson, Ralph M., "DUNEHILDE,", 1917 Oct; [Print. 2 7/8 in x 5 in] (Folder 1.2)
    - Pearson, Ralph M., "ELVERHOJ GREETINGS CHRISTMAS 1915,", 1914-1915; [Etching. 1 5/8 in x 3 3/8 in (top of sheet heavily stained). 2 copies] (Folder 1.2)
    - Pearson, Ralph M., "EX LIBRIS" (View of New York University Library by Stanford White), [Pencil drawing. 2 1/2 in x 4 1/2 in] (Folder 1.2)
    - Pearson, Ralph M., "EX-LIBRIS-HENRY-H-TIMKEN,", undated; [Etching, signed in pencil. 2 5/8 in x 4 3/8 in] (Folder 1.2)
    - Pearson, Ralph M., "EX LIBRIS VC 17,", [circa 1917]; [Print. 2 in x 3 in] (Folder 1.2)
    - Pearson, Ralph M., "A Portfolio of Original Etched Bookplates by Ralph M. Pearson," American Bookplate Society, 1912-1919; [Etching, signed in pencil. 6 in x 9 in. 12 prints] (Folder 1.63)
    - Pearson, Ralph M., "SEASON'S GREETINGS" (Adobe building with walled court, New Mexico?), [no year] Nov 21; [Etching, signed in pencil. 1 7/8 in x 3 5/8 in] (Folder 1.3)
    - Pearson, Ralph M., "The place where thine honor dwelleth,", 1914; [Etching. 3 in x 9 3/8 in] (Folder 1.64)
    - Pearson, Ralph M., Vassar College Library, undated; [Watercolor, pencil, and ink. 4 3/8 in x 6 in] (Folder 1.3)
    - Pearson, Ralph M., "VASSAR COLLEGE LIBRARY," drafts and alternate versions, undated; [Etching. Various sizes. 9 prints] (Folder 1.65)
    - Pearson, Ralph M., "VASSAR COLLEGE LIBRARY - HENRY NOBLE MACCRACKEN FUND,", 1925; [Print. 3 3/4 in x 6 5/8 in] (Folder 1.3)
    - Scott, [James], "Greetings,", undated; [Etching. 2 in x 4 in] (Folder 1.4)
    - Unknown artist, "Carl J. Smalley,", undated; [Print. 2 3/4 in x 7 in] (Folder 1.5)
    - Unknown artist, "A Christmas Carol & a wish for a happy new year from 3 Vandam,", undated; [Print. 4 in x 6 in] (Folder 1.5)
    - Unknown artist, "Christmas Greetings from Elverhoj,", undated; [Etching (laid down on gray paper). 2 7/8 in x 4 7/8 in] (Folder 1.5)
    - Unknown artist, "EX LIBRIS HARIET HERSLOFF,", undated; [Pencil. 3 1/8 in x 4 7/8 in] (Folder 1.5)
    - Unknown artist, "Greetings from Orchard Beach,", undated; [Pencil. 6 3/8 in x 7 3/4 in] (Folder 1.6)
    - Unknown artist, landscape with trees, undated; [Pencil. 3 1/2 in x 6 3/4 in] (Folder 1.6)
    - Unknown artist, landscape with trees ("EX LIBRIS" erased), undated; [Pencil. 3 1/2 in x 6 3/4 in] (Folder 1.6)
    - Unknown artist, room with stove, undated; [Print. 3 3/4 in x 5 3/4 in] (Folder 1.6)
    - Unknown artist, snow-covered house, undated; [Print and pastels. 6 1/2 in x 4 1/2 in] (Folder 1.6)
  - Craft Designs
    - [Petersen?], Four small drawings with bird motifs; two of four are for frames, undated; [Pencil.] (Folder 1.7)
    - Unknown artist, Escutcheon for keyhole, [190?]; [Pencil.] (Folder 1.8)
      In pencil: "Joseph Popelka" and "Roy Hutchinson." Reverse: printed form for invoice of "Racine School of Fine Arts" 190_.
    - Unknown artist(s), Escutcheons and other designs, undated; [Pencil.] (Folder 1.8)
    - Unknown artist, Three small drawings with floral motifs, undated; [Pencil.] (Folder 1.9)
      One with reverse printed: "Racine Commercial Art Department." One with plant forms surrounded by added black.
    - Unknown artist, Three small drawings on thin paper with [squid?] motifs, undated; [Pencil.] (Folder 1.10)
    - Unknown artist, Windmill and plant forms, front and back, undated; [Pencil.] (Folder 1.11)
  - Craft Renderings
    - Light Fixtures
      - Ceiling light fixture with three spherical bulbs in petal-like forms hanging from chains, undated; [Watercolor (suggesting copper). 13 15/16 in x 10 in] (Folder 4.1)
      - Ceiling light fixture consisting of large globe within circular metal frame incised with trefoil and other motifs, and candle holders attached to frame; also smaller version of the globe, undated; [Watercolor. 14 in x 19 in] (Folder 6.1 (Oversize))
      - Ceiling light fixture with square shade having a low pyramidal top, suspended from ceiling plate by 5 straps, undated; [Watercolor. 10 in x 14 in] (Folder 4.1)
      - Dragon Set: Ceiling and wall light fixtures and painting of Viking ships. Dragon heads holding candles, all in Gothic wood-truss ceiling, undated; [Watercolor. 14 in x 19 in] (Folder 6.2 (Oversize))
        In pencil: "This represents in a general way the connecting hall between the large dining halls—The painting suggested should have its counterpiece on the opposite gable facing the other dining room. The chandeliers throughout both halls should be the same-" Also in pencil: "Designed for Miss Covell/Special."
      - Dragon Set: Ceiling light fixture four dragon heads supporting candles and spherical globe within circular metal frame, undated; [Watercolor. 14 in x 15 3/8 in] (Folder 6.2)
      - Dragon Set: Ceiling light fixture with four dragon heads, but showing two fixtures suspended from Gothic wood-truss ceiling, undated; [Watercolor. 14 in x 13 3/8 in] (Folder 6.2 (Oversize))
      - Half-Dome Set: Ceiling light fixture with four candle holders attached to circular frame suspended on four chains (gold or brass and silver or steel version), undated; [Watercolor. 10 in x 14 in] (Folder 4.2)
      - Half-Dome Set: Ceiling light fixture with four candle holders attached to circular frame suspended on four chains (silver or steel version), undated; [Watercolor. 10 3/4 in x 16 1/4 in] (Folder 4.2)
      - Leaf Set: Ceiling light fixture with three spherical bulb topped with leaf patterns hanging by chains from circular relief medallion, undated; [Watercolor. 13 7/8 in x 8 7/8 in] (Folder 4.3)
        In pencil: "About 1/3 size"
      - Leaf Set: Wall sconce with curved bracket and spherical bulb with leaf ornament, undated; [Watercolor. 13 7/8 in x 9 7/8 in] (Folder 4.3)
        In pen and ink: "Designed for Mr. von Hoffman" In pencil: "About 2/3 size-"
      - Table lamp with copper shade and ornaments and gray metal base and frame, undated; [Watercolor. 14 in x 19 1/8 in] (Folder 6.3 (Oversize))
      - Wall light fixture, bulb hanging by chain from bracket attached to horizontal wall fixture, undated; [Watercolor (suggesting copper). 9 7/8 in x 14 7/8 in] (Folder 4.1)
        In pencil: "32.50 a pair" and "C... 706"
      - Wall sconce with bracket and spherical lamp bulb, three-lobed leaf motif, undated; [Watercolor. 10 in x 13 7/8 in] (Folder 4.4)
        Inscribed in ink: "Designed for Spencer Kellogg Jr." In pencil: "in copper 30—a pair--"
      - Wall sconce with curved bracket and lantern having door with latch, undated; [Watercolor. 11 3/8 in x 18 1/2 in (right side of paper trimmed away)] (Folder 6.3 (Oversize))
      - Wall sconce with curved bracket and lantern having trefoils, undated; [Watercolor (suggesting copper). 17 7/8 in x 18 5/8 in] (Folder 6.1 (Oversize))
      - Wall sconce with human face and curved bracket and spherical bulb with plant forms., undated; [Watercolor (suggesting copper). 14 in x 9 3/8 in] (Folder 4.4)
    - Jewelry
      - Bar pin, gold with red stone, undated; [Watercolor. 4 in x 3 5/8 in] (Folder 1.12)
        Stamped: "Elverhoj Colony of Artists & Craftsmen." Inscribed in ink: "Designed for Mrs. Norton."
      - Links, silver with inset polychrome oval, undated; [Watercolor. 3 3/4 in x 3 3/4 in] (Folder 1.12)
        Stamped "Elverhoj Colony Art Shop/Market & Cannon Sts./Poughkeepsie, N.Y." Pen and ink: "Links-Silver-Pair $10" and "Designed for Mrs. Norton."
      - Pendant with colorful floral group on chain, undated; [Watercolor. 3 1/4 in x 5 5/8 in. Framed] (Box 5)
        Stamped: "Elverhoj Colony of Artists & Craftsmen." Inscribed in ink: "Designed for Mrs. Doran."
      - Pendant with green stone and floral motifs, circa 1917; [Watercolor. 3 5/8 in x 5 5/8 in] (Folder 1.12)
      - "Shirt-waist set, actual size. Flora Americano. Corals and pearls,", undated; [Watercolor. 6 3/4 in x 3 in] (Folder 1.12)
    - Other Objects
      - Box with copper trim and hinges, undated; [Watercolor. 14 5/8 in x 10 1/8 in] (Folder 4.5)
        Faintly in pencil: "...this size $36.00"
      - Desk set with blotter, box, letter holder, ink well, and bud vase, undated; [Watercolor (suggesting copper). 16 1/8 in x 8 3/4 in] (Folder 4.5)
      - Desk set with blotter, box, letter holder, ink well, tray, and letter opener, undated; [Watercolor (gray, suggesting silver or steel). 14 in x 7 5/8 in] (Folder 4.5)
      - Vase with two handles, undated; [Watercolor (suggesting silver). 6 in x 13 1/8 in] (Folder 4.5)
    - Tableware
      - Pitcher with handle and spout, petal-like design, undated; [Watercolor (suggesting silver). 7 1/2 in x 9 1/8 in] (Folder 1.13)
      - Sugar bowl with two handles, petal-like design. Viewed from side and above, undated; [Watercolor (suggesting copper). 7 1/2 in x 10 in] (Folder 1.13)
      - Tea or coffee pot with creamer and sugar bowl on tray, undated; [Watercolor (suggesting copper). 14 7/8 in x 13 1/4 in (areas of dark stain)] (Folder 4.6)
      - Tea or coffee pot with petal-like design, undated; [Watercolor. 14 in x 9 1/2 in] (Folder 4.6)
  - Figures
    - Andersen, A. H., bare breasted woman, seated (signed), undated; [Pencil. 7 7/8 in x 9 7/8 in] (Folder 1.14)
    - Andersen, A. H., bare breasted woman, standing with cloth falling from her head over her torso (signed), undated; [Pencil. 5 1/4 in x 9 7/8 in] (Folder 1.14)
    - Andersen, A. H., Standing man, head lowered (signed in pencil), undated; [Pen and ink drawing, dense web of lines. 5 1/4 in x 10 in] (Folder 1.14)
    - Andersen, A. H., three figures fishing in small boat (signed), undated; [Pencil and ink. 8 5/8 in x 5 1/4 in] (Folder 1.14)
    - [Andersen, Anders H.?], Two trolls, one holding up a man, [no year] Oct 5; [Pen and ink and gray wash. 5 7/8 in x 8 7/8 in] (Folder 1.15)
      Reverse, in pencil: "October... Illustrating class"
    - Barbier, George, "L'Hiver,", 1925; [Print and pencil. 6 1/2 in x 10 1/4 in] (Folder 1.16)
    - Cole, Timothy. "Carrière. La Maternité. Luxembourg. Paris,", 1909; [Etching, matted. 16 in x 15 in] (Folder 6.4 (Oversize))
    - [J., F. T.], Two women walking at night in evening dress, undated; [Watercolor. 16 1/2 in x 15 1/4 in] (Folder 6.5 (Oversize))
    - Sunderland, [?], Cloaked woman, side profile, undated; [Watercolor. 5 1/2 in x 12 in] (Folder 4.7)
      In pencil: "in dark gray green mist"
    - Wendt, [?], woman standing in long skirt holding basket and staff (signed), 1901 Apr 25; [Pencil. 6 7/8 in x 10 in] (Folder 1.17)
    - Wendt, [?], young man standing in long coat (signed), 1901 Apr 25; [Pencil. 4 7/8 in x 8 3/8 in] (Folder 1.17)
    - Unknown artist, Boy playing a horn, undated; [Pencil and ink. 10 1/4 in x 8 1/4 in] (Folder 1.18)
      In pencil: "[Jun Ren?] Leo [Guardan?]"
    - Unknown artist, Five sketches on a sheet of paper (boy in shorts shown twice with net; bearded man with cap; standing figure in long coat; fence and cottage along roadside), undated; [Pencil. 7 in x 10 in] (Folder 1.18)
    - Unknown artist, Young woman standing in long coat and hat, undated; [Pen and ink over pencil. 8 in x 10 in] (Folder 1.18)
  - Landscapes
    - Andersen, A. H., Cows in landscape with trees, single cow on back (signed in pencil), undated; [Pencil drawing. 9 in x 5 3/8 in] (Folder 1.19)
    - Andersen, A. H., picturesque cottage on hillside (signed), [1905?]; [Pencil (mounted on paperboard). 5 3/4 in x 4 1/4 in] (Folder 4.8)
    - Andersen, A. H., "Trufant Lake—Mich—1902" (signed in pencil), [Pen and ink drawing. 9 7/8 in x 5 7/8 in] (Folder 1.20)
    - [Craig?], James, Tent on waterside surrounded by trees, undated; [Watercolor, graywash. 9 3/8 in x 14 1/4 in] (Folder 4.9)
    - Howard, E., "Old Tulip Tree,", 1934; [Print. 11 1/2 in x 16 in] (Folder 4.9)
    - Unknown artist, birch tree trunks (seven) in dark forest, undated; [Pen and black ink. 9 1/4 in x 14 in] (Folder 4.9)
    - Unknown artist, birch tree trunks with top of cabin visible, dense pen and ink strokes obscure lower part, undated; [Pen and ink. 7 7/8 in x 6 3/4 in (left edge tattered)] (Folder 1.21)
    - Unknown artist, Boats in a harbor at sunrise or sunset, undated; [Etching, signed in pencil. 21 1/2 in x 16 in] (Folder 6.6 (Oversize))
    - Unknown artist, cabin with door and horizontal window sheltered by tree, undated; [Pen and ink and gray wash. 4 1/2 in x 7 in] (Folder 1.22)
    - Unknown artist, Forest with branches in foreground, 1905 May; [Watercolor. 6 3/8 in x 10 in] (Folder 1.23)
    - Unknown artist, rocky shore, undated; [Watercolor. 6 7/8 in x 5 3/4 in] (Folder 1.21)
    - Unknown artist, ships moored at a dock, undated; [Pen. 8 3/4 in x 4 3/4 in] (Folder 1.21)
    - Unknown artist, Tent on platform in woods at Elverhoj, undated; [Watercolor, framed. 13 in x 15 1/4 in] (Box 5)
    - Unknown artist, tree trunk, roots, and branches with ground covered with rocks and flowers, undated; [Pen and ink with added white. 18 1/2 in x 21 1/2 in] (Folder 6.7 (Oversize))
      Three corners left blank with pencil note: "...[?] mortise"
  - Other Subjects
    - [Andersen, Anders H.?], "At the Gate to ELVERHOJ,", 1940 Nov 16; [Watercolor. 4 3/8 in x 8 3/8 in] (Folder 1.24)
    - [J., F. T.], Women in bonnets at street market, 1906; [Pastels. 19 3/4 in x 12 1/2 in] (Folder 6.5 (Oversize))
    - Pearson, Ralph M., Birch trees and a poem by Zona Gale, undated; [Print. 7 1/2 in x 14 1/2 in] (Folder 3.6)
    - Unknown artist, Bell with timber frame, undated; [Pencil. 6 in x 9 in] (Folder 1.25)
    - Unknown artist, Village with Gothic spire and illuminate windows, star in night sky, undated; [Watercolor on paper, 5 1/4 in x 7 7/8 in] (Folder 1.25)
      Reverse printed: "Bought of J. B. Sisson's Sons Auctioneers... 372 Main Street, [Poughkeepsie]"
  - Postcards
    - Pearson, Ronald to Anders H. Andersen, 1932 Dec 22; [Print. 5 1/2 in x 3 1/4 in] (Folder 1.26)
- Series II. Photographs, 1905-1934
  - Book stands, paper holders, and inkwells (Photographer: Petrus Forssbergs), undated; [8 photographs] (Folder 1.27)
  - Costumed girls. Four figures (two girls, two older), three with feathered headdresses. Outdoors with path at left, undated; [5 1/8 in x 3 1/4 in] (Folder 1.28)
  - Craftsman Erik Magnussen in necktie and white coat with hammer and tool working on bowl with other silver pieces displayed on table, undated; [13 3/4 in x 10 5/8 in] (Folder 4.10)
  - Furniture. Three small photos of bench; drop-leaf table; and these two joined with four chairs, undated; [Photos trimmed to outlines of furniture and pasted to brown backing. 3 photographs] (Folder 1.29)
  - Jewelry and Silverware, several labeled "Flora Americana,", 1926, undated; [6 photographs] (Folder 1.30)
  - Knitters. 25 young women, some with needles, others with knitting looms, [circa 1918?]; [Printed photograph] (Folder 1.31)
    On reverse, newspaper clipping: "War's Effect on Education." Argues for inclusion of arts in university life.
  - Light fixtures and candle holders (Photographer: Petrus Forssbergs), undated; [13 photographs] (Folder 1.32)
  - Man (Andersen?) seated by rocky stream in woods. At base of photo, hand-lettered: "ELVERHOJ—ANNO DOMINI—1934." On reverse: pen and ink of barren landscape with cut-out print of three masked men lifting daggers, [Collage. 8 in x 9 3/4 in] (Folder 1.33)
    Inscribed in pencil: "About all that was left of Elverhoj—during 1934."
  - Portrait of W. C. Fields, signed, 1905 Mar 28; [5 5/8 in x 10 in] (Folder 1.34)
    In pen: "To my esteemed friend Andersen. Sincerely, Mr. W. C. Fields"
  - Stands and hangers (Photographer: Petrus Forssbergs), undated; [3 photographs] (Folder 1.35)
  - Waterfall, undated; [3 3/8 in x 5 1/2 in] (Folder 1.36)
- Series III. Letters and Financial Records, 1914-1942, 1985
  - Central Hudson Gas and Electric, invoices, 1915-1916 (Folder 1.37)
  - Charles S. Platt Company, receipts and invoices, 1916, 1922 (Folder 1.38)
  - Elverhoj Account Book, "Basement Hall Collection" and "Quaker Road Pottery,", circa 1924 (Folder 2.1)
  - Letter from Howe, Louis McHenry to Anders H. Andersen, 1934 Feb 8; [Typewritten, signed, stamped "Newburgh Historical Society."] (Folder 1.39)
    On White House stationery, thanking Andersen for sending FDR birthday greetings and words of commendation on Jan 28.
  - Letter from Plog, Arthur P. (district Service Manager, Home Owners' Loan Corporation, Albany) to Mrs. Franklin D. Roosevelt, regarding the foreclosure of A. H. Andersen's property, 1935 Aug 1; [Typewritten, signed, stamped "Newburgh Historical Society."] (Folder 1.40)
  - Letter from Popchapin, M. M. (The Art Appreciation Movement) to Anders H. Andersen, and pamphlet, 1942 May 9; [Typewritten, signed.] (Folder 1.41)
  - Letter from Roosevelt, Eleanor to Anders H. Andersen, 1935 Jul 24; [Typewritten, signed, stamped "Newburgh Historical Society."] (Folder 1.42)
  - Letter from Roosevelt, Eleanor to Anders H. Anderson, 1935 Aug 6; [Typewritten, signed, stamped "Newburgh Historical Society."] (Folder 1.42)